CHEN Lihsuan

陳 澧菅

vince78718@gmail.com · +81-80-4444-8416 · GitHub: @vc7 · https://giita.com/vc7

Speak Mandarine (Native), English (TOEIC 860) and Japanese (JLPT N1)

iOS Engineer

Bring better and colorful life to the world through engineering

Starting with frontend and backend development since student-era. Having more than 6-year-career, since 2012, as an iOS app developer that have experience and good at app developing, member mentoring, team enhancement and problem solving. Having UI design and user experience evaluation skills to improving products or services.

Key Software Skills

- iOS app development and tests using Swift, Objective-C
 - Libraries: RxSwift, AFNetworking, Alamofire, Kingfisher
- · Designing app functionalities and user experience to fit services
- · REST/RESTful API, have knowledge of collaborating and designing with teams
- · Workflow automation using Travis CI, CircleCI, Fastlane and Deploygate

Other Skills

- Familiar with the steps from planing products with cross functional team, implementing to releasing
- Evaluating tools or services and introducing them to the teams
- Making UI's wireframes and mocks, user experience evaluation, using Photoshop, Illustrator, Sketch
- · Frontend development, using JavaScript, CSS, Bootstrap and jQuery
- Backend development, using Python and Node.js
- Mentoring new members in the teams
- Scrum/agile-liked teams
- · Business model planing, lean methods

Professional Experience

BASE Inc., seconded to PAY Inc., Tokyo, Japan **Engineer** (April 2017 - Present)

Responsible for - PAY ID (Main, iOS app, QR code payment service), EC app (iOS app, able to start an EC shop in the app, project closed), PAY.JP iOS SDK (iOS SDK, to let developers able to use the online payment service PAY.JP in their apps)

- · Mainly in main service's iOS app and SDK development and maintenance Swift, RxSwift
- · Architecture Enhancement Embedded framework
- · Workflow automation Travis CI, CircleCI, Fastlane, DeployGate
- Fetch and analyze app reports automatically Python, CircleCI
- UI/UX wireframe, enhancement and design proposals Sketch, Illustrator, Zeplin
- Business enhancement and data analyzation proposals
- Team size 4~6 members (1~2 iOS members) GitHub Projects, Asana

Gamania Digital Entertainment, Taipei, Taiwan Contract iOS Engineer (Jan 2016 - Nov 2016)

Responsible for - All people (iOS app for TV program, realtime interaction), Coture (iOS app for live video and chatting app), EC Platform (iOS app for shopping agent platform, not public yet)

- · Mainly in new services' iOS app development Objective-C, Swift
- · Lead the researching and implementing streaming and chatting functionality
- Introduced GitHub Flow, Kanban and Scrum to the team
- Mentored new team members, improved the performance of the team members
- Organized 4-week Git lessons for the team, with over 10 members participated
- Team size 4~6 members (1~2 iOS members) Team Foundation Server

Spring House Entertainment Technology Inc., Taipei, Taiwan **iOS Engineer** (Aug 2014 - Aug 2015)

Responsible for - Kollect Life (iOS app, reading social platform, project closed), Kollect Point (iOS app, coupon exchange platform, project closed)

- · Mainly in new services' iOS app development Objective-C, Swift
- · Refactoring existing iOS projects
- Introduced Git (svn while joined), Git Flow, GitHub Flow to the team
- Main member of new project startup using lean method and business planning
- Organized an iOS team with group of 3 engineers
- · Evaluated external services such as API host services and OCR services
- UI/UX wireframe, enhancement and design proposals Illustrator
- Scrum team 4~9 members (1~4 iOS members) Redmine

Efwuhn Inc., Taipei, Taiwan **Mobile Software Engineer** (Aug 2013 - Jun 2014)

Responsible for - TallyUp (iOS app to help people that are shopping in Costco, service stopped)

- Mainly in experiment project's iOS app development Objective-C
- Frontend Angular
- · Backend (cloud function, API development on Parse) Node.js, Express
- · Evaluated multiple MBaaSs
- UI wireframe and design, UX enhancement proposal.
- Scrum team 2~3 members (2 iOS member)

Ans Global Corporation, Taipei, Taiwan Chief Development Officer of iOS (Feb. 2013 - Jul. 2013)

Responsible for - **PASSbank** (iOS app. Shop owners are able to manage its members' points thru the app, service stopped)

- iOS app development Objective-C
- · Dashboard, API development, push notification LAMP
- Web development ¡Query, CSS/LESS
- UI wireframe and design Hand drawing, Photoshop, Illustrator
- Introduced Git, GitHub Flow to the team.
- Team size 2~3 members (1 iOS member)

Education

National Changhua University of Education, Changhua, Taiwan Bachelor of Business Administration, 2011